adrianpelletier.com 2018-09-30

# Privacy Policy – Adrian Pelletier

## Summary

We (http://www.adrianpelletier.com) value your privacy as much as we do our own, so we’re committed to keeping your information safe. This privacy policy outlines what personal data we collect and why we collect it.

### Your contact information

  * If you contact us by email through our website, we collect your name, email address, and any other information you’ve given us in the email.
  * Occasionally, we might receive your contact information from one of our partners. If we do, we protect it in exactly the same way as if you give it to us directly.
  * If you sign up for our newsletter, we store your email address in MailChimp, which is the marketing platform we prefer. You can unsubscribe to our newsletter at any time.
  * If you leave a comment, we collect the submitted data as described below.

### Your comments

If you leave comments on this website, we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

Additionally, you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this website may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Links

This website contains links to other sites.  Please be aware that we are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of such other sites.  We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of any other site that collects personally identifiable information.

### Free Design Resources

We occasionally offer free design resources via download links on this website. These resources are royalty-free for use in both personal and commercial projects.

You are permitted to use the resources in any number of personal and commercial projects for yourself or for a client. You may modify the resources according to your requirements and include them into works such as websites, applications, printed materials and others. No attribution or link back to this site is required, although any credit will be much appreciated.

However, you do not have the rights to resell, sublicense or redistribute (even for free) the files on their own or as a separate attachment from any of your work. If you wish to promote my resources on your site, you must link back to the resource page where users can find the download and not directly to the download file.

These resources and documentation, if any, are provided “as is” with no warranty expressed or implied. In no event shall www.adrianpelletier.com or its owners be liable for any direct, indirect, incidental, special, exemplary, or consequential damages arising in any way out of the use of these resources.

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics (Google Inc.) to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of visitor behavior.

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services. Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage Data.

Place of processing: United States – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en).

### Advertising

Ads appearing on our website may be delivered by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile non-personal identification information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This privacy policy does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers.

### How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

### What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this website, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### How we protect your data

While no online service is 100% secure, we take precautions to protect your information. We store passwords in 1Password, an encrypted password manager, use a different, randomly generated password for each service, and never use the same password twice.

The computers we use are protected by a passcode. These computers ask for authentication whenever they’re started or after 5 minutes of inactivity. Our mobile devices are also protected by a passcode.

### Changes to this Privacy Policy

Our Privacy Policy may change any time. When this occurs, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. We encourage you to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications.

### Your acceptance of these terms

By using this website, you signify your acceptance of this policy and terms of service. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our website. Your continued use of the website following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.

### Updates

_This document was last updated on August 1, 2018_

### Contact us

If you have any questions or concerns related to this privacy policy, please contact us at: info@adrianpelletier.com
